Guide to the Mary Beth Edelson Papers MSS.549
Fales Library and Special Collections
Mary Beth Edelson Papers
1950-2016
1970-2010
Fales Library and Special Collections
Edelson, Mary Beth
MSS.549
60.84 Linear Feet in 114 manuscript boxes, 1 half manuscript box, 10 flat boxes, 11 oversized flat boxes, and 6 oversized flat file folders.
6.15 Gigabytes in 100 digital files
Mary Beth Edelson (1933-2021) was an American artist whose work included printmaking, book art, sculpture, collage art, painting, photography, performance art, and writing. Her feminist and conceptual art often challenged patriarchal systems. The Mary Beth Edelson Papers (1950-2016) consist of materials created and collected by Edelson and document her artistic process and output, as well as her role in the American feminist art movement. Materials in this collection include correspondence, grant applications, exhibition ephemera, art books, publications, photographs, slides of works and exhibitions, clippings of reviews and press releases, original notebooks, original sketchbooks, visual source materials, and subject files concerning themes pertinent to Edelson's work. This collection also includes materials documenting Edelson's personal life, her involvement with the feminist artist cooperative A.I.R. Gallery (Artists in Residence) and the women's rights organization Women's Action Coalition (WAC). The collection also contains digital photographs of an Edelson collage featured as part of a Louise Bourgeois exhibition at the Tate Modern, as well as digital photographs and documents related to the creation of an A.I.R. Gallery book.
Biographical Note
Mary Beth Edelson (1933-2021) was an American artist whose work included printmaking, book art, sculpture, collage art, painting, photography, performance art, and writing. Edelson studied at the Art Institute of Chicago as a teenager and then earned a Bachelor of Arts degree from DePauw University in 1955. She later earned her Master of Fine Arts from New York University in 1958.
Edelson was a prominent artist within the feminist art movement in the United States, which began in the late 1960s and early 1970s. Her feminist and conceptual art often challenged patriarchal systems and included themes such as ancient goddess figures, nude female bodies, notable historical scenes, and popular culture. In 1968, Edelson established the Conference for Women in the Visual Arts (CWVA) and in the late 1970s, she joined the feminist art cooperative, A.I.R. Gallery (Artists in Residence), and the feminist political arts group, Heresies Collective.
Edelson's works have been exhibited domestically and internationally at institutions including the Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) in New York City and the Malmo Museum in Sweden. Some of her notable works include Some Living American Women Artists (1972), Memorial to 9,000,000 Women Burned as Witches in the Christian Era (1977), Kali Bobbitt (1994), and Story Gathering Boxes (1972-2021).
Edelson was also an arts educator and taught at a variety of locations including Chicago, Michigan, Minneapolis, and Pennsylvania. She also taught a nine-week women's study course in art at the Smithsonian Institute in Washington, D.C.
In addition to her life as a working artist, Edelson was an advocate for women's rights and a vocal opponent of domestic violence. From 1992-1994, Edelson served as the leader of the Women's Action Coalition's Committee on Diveristy and Inclusion. She also worked closely with Combat Zone: Campaign HQ Against Domestic Violence.
Scope and Contents
The Mary Beth Edelson Papers (1950-2016) consist of materials created and collected by Edelson and document her life as a working artist, feminist, and activist. The collection contains correspondence, grant applications, exhibition ephemera, art books, publications, photographs, slides of works and exhibitions, clippings of reviews and press releases, visual source materials, as well as subject files. Together, these materials highlight the types of exhibitions Edelson participated in, her various inspirations for art pieces, and the ways in which she was perceived by her colleagues and critics. Edelson's notebooks and sketchbooks document her artistic processes, providing further context about her life as an artist. These materials also reflect Edelson's affiliation and participation with A.I.R. Gallery (Artists in Residence). An overarching theme within Edelson's art is the power of the Goddess and the nude female body. This imagery appears frequently in the artwork found in both Series I: Professional Activities and Series III: A.I.R. Gallery.
Edelson participated in numerous women's rights and anti-domestic violence protests, fundraisers, and charity events. Edelson's activism with the Women's Action Coalition (WAC) and Combat Zone: Campaign HQ Against Domestic Violence are documented through posters for events and organizations, photographs, flyers, slides, feminist essays, correspondence, press releases, and artwork.
In addition to Edelson's life as an artist and activist, the collection contains materials related to Edelson's personal life and interests through correspondence with her family, alumni bulletins published by her alma mater DePauw University, her college-era sketchbooks, anti-war ephemera, and personal travel materials.
The collection also contains digital photographs of an Edelson collage featured as part of a Louise Bourgeois exhibition at the Tate Modern, as well as digital photographs and documents related to the creation of an A.I.R. Gallery book.
Arrangement
The collection has been arranged topically into the following series and sub-series:
Series I: Professional Activities
Sub-Series I.A: Original Works
Sub-Series I.B: Exhibitions and Performances
Sub-Series I.C: Research Materials
Sub-Series I.D: Teaching, Conferences, Workshops, and Affiliations
Sub-Series I.E: Reviews, Writings, and Interviews
Sub-Series I.F: Thematic Interests
Sub-Series I.G: Administrative Files
Series II: Women's Action Coalition (WAC)
Series III: A.I.R. Gallery
Series IV: Personal Materials
Materials have been arranged alphabetically by file title within each series and sub-series.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by the family of Mary Beth Edelson in September and October 2018; the accession numbers associated with this gift are 2018.102 and 2018.111.
Born-Digital Access Policies and Procedures
An access terminal for born-digital materials in the collection is available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Researchers may view an item's original container and/or carrier, but the physical carriers themselves are not available for use because of preservation concerns.
Related Materials
A.I.R. Gallery Archives (MSS.184)
Feminism and art.; Art, American -- 20th century; Drawings (visual works); Sketchbooks.; Artists.; Photographs.; Posters.; Notebooks; Art Books; Correspondence.; Slides (photographs); Clippings files.; Research notes.; Washington (D.C.); A.I.R. Gallery (New York, N.Y.); New York (N.Y.).; Domestic Violence -- Prevention & Control; Edelson, Mary Beth; Bobbitt, Lorena; Women's Action Coalition (New York, N.Y.)
- Series I: Professional Activities, 1950-2016 (inclusive); 1970-2016 (bulk); 53.99 Linear Feet in 100 manuscript boxes, 10 flat boxes, 11 oversized flat boxes, and 6 oversized folders
  Scope and Contents
  Series I: Professional Activities focuses on Mary Beth Edelson's career as a working artist, author, member of feminist art organizations, and arts educator. Materials in this series include correspondence, art books, lecture notes, posters, grant applications, administrative paperwork, exhibition ephemera, publications, photographic slides of works and exhibitions, reviews and press releases, original notebooks, original sketchbooks, original artwork, visual source materials, and subject files.
  Arrangement
  Materials in this series have been arranged into seven sub-series by topic and then alphabetically arranged within those sub-series by file title.
  - Sub-series I.A: Original Works, 1950-2009 (inclusive); 1968-2009 (bulk); 23.08 Linear Feet in 30 manuscript boxes, 10 flat boxes, 10 oversized flat boxes, and 4 oversized folders
    Sub-Series I.A focuses on Mary Beth Edelson's original artwork and sketches. The sub-series contains Edelson's numerous artbooks including The Archeology of Trickster Rabbit in Re-Cycled Time (1981), Fish in the Sky (1985), her Unfinished Plans for Utopia series (circa 1980s), and her Winged Rocks series (1978-1979). The sub-series also contains examples of Edelson's photography projects including Goddess Head, Kitty Hawk, Fire Rings, and Women Rising. A recurring motif in Edelson's artwork is the nude female body and this is particularly prevalent in her photographs. Edelson's many sketchbooks can also be found in Sub-Series I.A, which feature ideas for art pieces, exhibitions, and some drawings from her travels. Slides of Edelson's drawings and paintings, as well as copies of her original artwork are also housed within this sub-series. Digital photographs of one of Edelson's collages, which was featured at the Tate Modern as part of a Louise Bourgeois exhibition, are contained within this sub-series.
    - 50s, 60s, 70s Paintings (Slides), undated (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - 60s Art, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Alice's Dream, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 2, Box 109, Folder 1)
    - Andy Warhol, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Aprons (Slides), 1991-1996 (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - Art Book - Aging in Diana's Grove, undated (Box 123, Folder 1)
    - Art Book - The Archaeology of Trickster Rabbit in Re-Cycled Time, 1981 (Box 123, Folder 2)
    - Art Book - Barely A Ladder (Series: Lesser Known Goddesses - Bear Ladder), 1980 (Box 123, Folder 3)
    - Art Book - The Birds, 1963 (Box 123, Folder 4)
    - Art Book - Burning Images, 1979 (Box 123, Folder 5)
    - Art Book - Calling Spirit, circa 1978 (Box 128)
    - Art Book - Comforting Mountain, 1978 (Box 123, Folder 6)
    - Art Book - Comforting Mountain Shelter: Pink Interior, 1980 (Box 132)
    - Art Book - Dancing Caves (from the series The Archaeology of Trickster Rabbit in Re-Cycled Time), 1981 (Box 132)
    - Art Book - Europe etc, 1958 (Box 123, Folder 7)
    - Art Book - Fish in the Sky, 1985-1986 (Box 123, Folder 8)
    - Art Book - Freeing Rocks: A Good Day's Work, 1979 (Box 124, Folder 1)
    - Art Book - A Healing Ritual: Men and Women, 1986 (Box 130)
    - Art Book - Heavy Rocks/Light Wings -- Light Rocks Heavy Wings III (Winged Rocks Series II), 1979 (Box 124, Folder 2)
    - Art Book - How Did You Get So Free?, undated (Box 124, Folder 3)
    - Art Book - How to Walk Away: The Sacred Manic Goddess Makes Tracks, 1978 (Box 124, Folder 4)
    - Art Book - Journey Rug, 1975 (Box 124, Folder 5)
    - Art Book - Lines, 1978 (Box 124, Folder 6)
    - Art Book - Memorials to the 9,000,000 Women Burned as Witches in the Christian Era, 1977 (Box 125, Folder 1)
    - Art Book - The Messages to the Goddess, circa 1979-1982 (Box 125, Folder 2)
    - Art Book - Mother Is Dying, circa 1985 (Box 125, Folder 3)
    - Art Book - Mushroom Paintings, 1978 (Box 125, Folder 4)
    - Art Book - New Harmony Wood Cut Portfolio & Bronzes & Prints, 1985 (Box 125, Folder 5)
    - Art Book - No Short Strings, 1986 (Box 128)
    - Art Book - NYC '50s, 1958 (Box 125, Folder 6)
    - Art Book - Performance of 'Fire Flights in Deep Space" - The Script and the Photographs, 1978 (Box 126, Folder 1)
    - Art Book - Reading Between the Ashes: Fire and Ice, undated (Box 126, Folder 2)
    - Art Book - Rough Drafts, 1977-1979 (Box 126, Folder 3)
    - Art Book - See For Yourself: Pilgrimage to a Neolithic Cave 1977 - Yugoslavia - Hvar Island near Jelsa village of Humac (Box 126, Folder 4)
    - Art Book - Stone Speaks, 1977 (Box 126, Folder 5)
    - Art Book - Summer Workbook - Port Clyde, Maine, 1978 (Box 133)
    - Art Book - The Thunder Perfect Trickster, 1978-1984 (Box 133)
    - Art Book - Tides & Sky, 1982 (Box 126, Folder 6)
    - Art Book - (Unfinished) Plans for Utopia: 1978/1987, undated (Box 127, Folder 1)
    - Art Book - (Unfinished) Plans for Utopia -- Making Room for New Life, undated (Box 127, Folder 2)
    - Art Book - (Unfinished) Plans for Utopia -- Planning Sessions, circa 1980s (Box 127, Folder 3)
    - Art Book - (Unfinished) Plans for Utopia -- Underground Earth Movement: Splits Three and Rises, 1980 (Box 129)
    - Art Book - Untitled Book of Hand Photographs, undated (Box 130)
    - Art Book - Walking Away, 1976-1977 (Box 127, Folder 4)
    - Art Book - We Are All Mushrooms, 1973 (Box 127, Folder 5)
    - Art Book - Winged Rocks, 1976-1979 (Box 129, Box 131)
    - Art Books and Exhibitions (Slides), 1970-1980 (Box 88, Folder 3-4)
    - Art Park/Diana's Grove (Photographs), undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Baby Book, undated (Box 108)
    - Bad Art by Men, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Bamberg Book, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Black & White Photographs (Slides), circa 1970s (Box 88, Folder 5)
    - Body (Photographs), 1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - The Body Pumpkin, Emison Art Center (Slides), 1990 (Box 88, Folder 6)
    - Bodyworks/Firsthand, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Book of Bad Habits (Box 108)
    - The Book of the Nature Balancing, 1979 (Box Shared Fales 042, Folder 4-11)
    - Boxes (Slides), 1972-1979 (Box 88, Folder 7)
    - Bronze Sculptures, 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Carolee, Live - Photograph Performance (Slides), 1987 (Box 88, Folder 8)
    - Cave Widow Jane (Photographs), 1992 (Box 1, Folder 10-12)
    - Celebrity Masks, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Chico Mountains (Photographs), undated (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
    - City Flowers of the World, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Collage (Slides), 1971-1976 (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Comic Book, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Dancing Goddess Book, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Demeter, Kore, and Persephone (Montauk, NY) (Photographs), undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Diana's Grove and Blanks (Maine) (Photographs), 1975 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Documenting Dreams, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Double Exposure (Photographs), undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Drawings (Slides), circa 1970s - 1980s (Box 3, Folder 1-3, Box 89, Folder 2-5, Box 90, Box 91, Box 92, Folder 1-8)
      The slides found within these folders contain a variety of drawings related to topics including Baubo, Sheela, movie stars, classical fishheads, goddesses, Lorena Bobbitt, and flying rocks. The slides also contain drawings related to exhibitions including Chiffon, Trickster, and No More Nice Girls.
    - Early Indiana & Rituals (Photographs), 1970 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Early Work, Paintings (Slides), circa 1950s (Box 92, Folder 9)
    - Earth W.K. Drawings (Slides), circa 1970s (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - East Villlage (Photographs), 1984 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Elise Meyers Leaping Lizzards, Speaking Bitterness, Utopia (Slides), 1980-1981 (Box 93, Folder 2)
    - Fire Feet - Studio (Photographs), undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Fire Rings (Photographs and Slides), 1975 (Box 3, Folder 7-10, Box 4, Folder 1-3, Box 93, Folder 3-4)
    - Fish in the Sky (Slides), 1985-1986 (Box 93, Folder 5)
    - Furniture (Photographs), undated (Box 109, Folder 2)
    - Goddess Head (Montauk) (Photographs), 1975 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Goddess Series Paintings/Drawings (Slides), 1970-1971 (Box 93, Folder 6)
    - Goddess Tribe, Henri - D.C. (Slides), circa 1970s (Box 93, Folder 7-8)
    - Hands (Photographs), 1977 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - High Fall Rapids (Photographs), undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - High Performance - "Speaking Bitterness: A Purification Rite for Deep Water" (Mary Beth Edelson, Cheryl Lynn Bruce), 1981 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Iceland (Photographs), 1977-1979 (Box 4, Folder 8-10)
    - Installations - P.P.O.W. Bedsheets (Slides), 1992-2004 (Box 93, Folder 9)
    - Just Looking: Mary Beth Interviews for a New Mate (Performance), undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - K Photo Performance (Slides), circa 1970s (Box 93, Folder 10)
    - Kitty Hawk (Photographs), circa 1970s (Box 5, Folder 2-7)
    - Light Feet (Photographs), undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Lorena Bobbitt, 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 1-5, Box 93, Folder 11, Box 117, Box 118)
      Materials in these folders and boxes relate to Mary Beth Edelson's various Lorena Bobbitt inspired art projects including Burn in Hell, Kali Bobbitt, Love Hurts, The Last Temptation of Lorena Bobbitt, and St. Bobbitt.
    - Maine House (Slides), 1978-1984 (Box 93, Folder 12)
    - Maine, Montauk, and Tassehara Mix (Slides), undated (Box 93, Folder 13)
    - Making Peace, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Mary Beth Edelson Gallery Presentation (Slides), 2005 (Box 93, Folder 14)
    - Mary Beth Edelson at Tate Modern (Louise Bourgeois Installation), 2007; cuid39077 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_549_ER_1)
    - Mary Beth Edelson Various Art Pieces (Slides), undated (Box 94, Folder 1-2)
    - Mixed Projects - Kitty Hawk, Fire Ring, Women Rising, undated (Box 6, Folder 7, Box 94, Folder 3)
    - Montauk, New York (Photographs), 1975-1978 (Box 6, Folder 8-9, Box 7, Folder 1-5)
    - Moon Mouth (Photographs and Slides), 1979 (Box 7, Folder 6, Box 94, Folder 4)
    - Mounted Sunset Color, Montauk Beach (Photographs), undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Nothing to Hide, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - NYC (Photographs), circa 1970s, 1993, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 9-10)
    - Original Art Board, undated (Box 109, Folder 3, Box 120, Folder 8)
    - Original Art Board - Half Tone, undated (Box 109, Folder 4-6)
    - Original Artwork, undated (Box 8, Folder 1-2, Box 109, Folder 7-15)
    - Original Artwork - Baubo/Sheela (Xeroxes), undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Original Artwork - Death to the Patriarchy, undated (Box 112, Folder 5)
    - Original Artwork - Female Boxer, undated (Box 120, Folder 10)
    - Original Artwork - Gloria Grahame, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Original Artwork - Handmade Signs, undated (Box 120, Folder 11)
    - Original Artwork - Judy Garland, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Original Artwork, Notes, and Photographs, undated (Box 8, Folder 6-8)
    - Original Artwork - Portrait Behind the Desk Series, 2005-2006 (Box 8, Folder 9, Box 109, Folder 16)
    - Original Artwork and Sketches, undated (Box 9, Folder 1-2, Box 109, Folder 17-18, Box 112, Folder 7-18)
    - Original Artwork and Sketches, undated (Box 113, Folder 1-6, Box 116, Folder 11-13, Box 120, Folder 13-14)
    - Original Artwork and Sketches -- Wall Paintings, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 3, Box 112, Folder 6)
    - Original Artwork - Stop Domestic Violence, undated (Box 120, Folder 15-16)
    - Original Collage Artwork, undated (Box 110, Folder 1, Box 113, Folder 7-18, Box 114, Folder 1-4)
    - Original Collage Artwork and Clippings, undated (Box 9, Folder 4, Box 114, Folder 5)
    - Original Drawings, undated, 1977 (Box 110, Folder 2-4)
    - Original Drawings - Double Headed Axe, 1975 (Box 110, Folder 5)
    - Original/Exhibit Ready Photographs Without Artwork, 1970-1985 (Box 9, Folder 5-6)
    - Paintings (Slides), undated (Box 9, Folder 7, Box 94, Folder 5-10, Box 95, Folder 1-6)
    - People/Mary Beth Edelson (Slides), undated (Box 95, Folder 7)
    - Photographs and Slides, 1973-1987 (Box 9, Folder 8-11, Box 10, Folder 1-5, Box 95, Folder 8-9)
    - Polyester Film Pad, undated (Box 116, Folder 7-8)
    - Posters, circa 1970s (Box 95, Folder 10, Flat-file-folder 2, Flat-file-folder 4, Flat-file-folder 2 Right)
    - Posters - Bringing Home the Evolution (Slides), 1978 (Box 96, Folder 1)
    - Posters - Death of the Patriarchy, Heresies, A.I.R. (Slides), 1976 (Box 96, Folder 2)
    - Posters - Hey Judy, Show Us Your Tits!", undated (Flat-file-folder 1 Right)
    - Posters - Some Living American Women Artists/Last Supper (Slides), 1972 (Box 96, Folder 3)
    - Prints of Mary Beth Edelson's Photographs, undated (Box 114, Folder 13, Box 120, Folder 19)
    - Prints, Photographs, Documentation, Posters, 1974-2007 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Prints & Woodcuts (Slides), 1985 (Box 96, Folder 4)
    - Private Rituals (Book Mockup), undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Ritual with Children (Photographs), 1970-1973 (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
    - Rocks (Drawings), undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Sculpture - Bronzes and Buddhas (Slides), 1970-1986 (Box 96, Folder 5-6)
    - SFA1/JFK (Photographs), undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Sheela Drawings (Slides), 1973-1996 (Box 96, Folder 7)
    - A Short Interpretive History of the Femme Fatale in Hollywood Films, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Sketchbooks, 1968-2009 (Box 11, Folder 6-9, Box 12, Folder 1-4, Box 114, Folder 20-23, Box 115, Folder 1-6)
    - Sketchbooks, 1968-2009 (Box 116, Folder 14-16, Box 119, Folder 1-3, Box 120, Folder 20, Box Shared Fales 086, Folder 10-12)
    - Sketches for Artwork on Photos, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Sketches - Making Peace & Community, undated (Box 119, Folder 4-5)
    - Slides - General Information, 1961-1988 (Box 12, Folder 6-7, Box 96, Folder 8, Box Shared Fales 042)
    - Stencil Paintings (Slides), 1987-1991 (Box 96, Folder 9)
    - Stolen Paintings - Artworks, 1996, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Studio - Two Journeys Wall Painting (Slides), 1988 (Box 96, Folder 10)
    - This is What 64 Looks Like Series (Slides), 1997 (Box 96, Folder 11)
    - Uncolonized Female Subjects 1975 (Box 13, Folder 1, Box 110, Folder 6)
    - Upstate, Miscellaneous, None Published (Photographs), 1992 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Wall Paintings - Mix (Slides), 1986-1989 (Box 96, Folder 12)
    - Washington, D.C. - Symbols, undated (Box 13, Folder 3-6)
    - Widow Jane's Cave (High Falls, NY) (Photographs), undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Widow Jane's - On Table (Photographs), 1992, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 2-3)
    - Winter's Alchemy, Photographic Research Center, Boston (Slides), 1989 (Box 97, Folder 1)
    - Women (Photographs), undated (Box 14, Folder 4-6)
    - Women Rising (Photographs), undated (Box 14, Folder 7-8, Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Women Rising: Sky (Photographs), undated (Box 15, Folder 2-3)
    - W.R. Sea (Photographs), undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Xerox Copies of Slides - Mix of Performance Ritual Photos, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Sub-Series I.B: Exhibitions and Performances, 1967-2016 (inclusive); 1970-2016 (bulk); 14.27 Linear Feet in 23 manuscript boxes, 1 flat box, 6 oversized flat boxes, and 2 oversized folders
    Sub-Series I.B focuses upon Mary Beth Edelson's exhibitions and performances such as 22 Others, Chiffons, Making Eye Contact, Portrait Project, Re-Scripting the Story: Mary Beth Edelson 1970-2000, Sexual Fantasies, Shapeshifters, and Story Gathering Boxes. These projects were displayed in museums and galleries across the United States, including New York, Illinois, California, New Jersey, and Texas, as well as internationally in countries including Sweden, France, Germany, Canada, and the United Kingdom. Materials related to these exhibitions and performances consist of slides and photographs, loan agreements, exhibition ephemera, posters, correspondence with museums and galleries, as well as exhibition drafts.
    Edelson was also featured as part of WACK!: Art and the Feminist Revolution, a traveling exhibition of international women's art that was presented at the Museum of Contemporary Art in Los Angeles and then PS1 Contemporary Art Center between 2007-2008. Mock-ups of the exhibition catalog and copies of Edelson's contribution to the project can be found within this sub-series.
    - 22 Others (Solo Exhibition), 1973, 2013 (Box 15, Folder 6-8, Box 16, Folder 1-3, Box 97, Folder 2)
    - Boston, 1985-1997 (Box 16, Folder 4-8, Box 97, Folder 2-3)